Archives Organization File Additional records 5956
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Box 5, Folder (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: Clyde Enterprise Newspaper, Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
    By Clyde Porcelain Steel Corporation. May 11, 1950 issue; large newspaper. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: How Can Supervisor and Employee Understanding of Business and Economc Be Improved, Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
    By C. G. MacAndrews. Transcript of an address given before the Industrial Relations Conference. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: How Can Better Understanding Between Management and Employees Be Brought About, Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
    By Stacy R. Black. Trancscript of address given at industrial relations conference. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Early Experiments in Workers' Education, Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
    By Amy Hewes. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: University Extension and Workers' Education, Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
    By Alfred P. Fernbach. July 1, 1945. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: A World of New Service for You If S-1390 The Labor Extension Service Bill is Passed, Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Item 8: A World of New Service for You If S-1390 The Labor Extension Service Bill is Passed, Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
    By AFL-CIO. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Wartime Developments in Workers' Education, Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Item 10: Workers' Education Material, Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
    By American Labor Education Service. List of education material prepared by twelve different workers' education agencies. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Your Stake in Profits, Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
    By American Iron and Steel Institute. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: Steve Merritt, Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
    By Teamwork Publications, Inc. Comic book. Item is in English.
- Box 5, Folder (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Higher Education, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
    By Andrew J. Biemiller. May 28, 1963. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Better Schools for a Better America, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 3: Teaching High School Students About Labor Unions, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 4: Labor Champion of Public Education, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 5: Policy Resolutions on Education, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 6: Labor Looks at Education, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Box 5, Folder (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Financing the Schools, Publication (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Item 2: The Anti-Labor Bias in Schoolbooks, Publication (Box 5, Folder 7)
    By Will Scoggins. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Improve Education About Unions in the Schools, Publication (Box 5, Folder 7)
    By UAW. Small Poster. Item is in English.
- Box 5, Folder (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: The Volunteer in Vocational Education, Publication (Box 5, Folder 8)
    By Samuel M. Burt. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Industry-Education Projects, Publication (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Box 5, Folder (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Are We Educating Our Children for the Wrong Future?, Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
    By Robert Maynard Hutchins. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: How to Pay for Higher Education, Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
    By Charles C. Killingsworth. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: School Employee-Management Relations Information Program - 1966-67, Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
    By Michigan State University, School of Labor and Industrial Relations. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: A Guide to Collective Negotiations in Education, Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
    By Charles T. Schmidt, Jr.; Hyman Parker; Bob Repas. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Manpower Education in a Growing Economy, Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
    By Robert L. Darcy; Phillip E. Powell. Item is in English.
- Box 5, Folder (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Bibliography No. XIV: Disadvantaged Groups, Publication (Box 5, Folder 10)
    By University of Wisconsin, Industrial Relations Research Institute. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Facts and Fancies about Automation, Publication (Box 5, Folder 10)
    By Patrick M. Boarman. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Education and Training: The Bridge Between Man and His Work, Publication (Box 5, Folder 10)
    By U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare. April 1, 1965. Item is in English.
- Box 5, Folder (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: The University, Publication (Box 5, Folder 11)
    By A. Whitney Griswold. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Selectred References: Educational Investment in Manpower Development, Publication (Box 5, Folder 11)
    By Princeton University. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Some Constitutional Prohibitions Against Financial Aid to Private Schools, Publication (Box 5, Folder 11)
    By American Federation of Teachers. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Contemporary Values and the Responsibility of the College, Publication (Box 5, Folder 11)
    By Jack F. Culley. Item is in English.
- Box 5, Folder (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Academic Unions, Values, and Democracy, Publication (Box 5, Folder 12)
    By Robert M. Nielsen; Irwin H. Polishook. Item is in English.
- Box 5, Folder (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: New Currents in Education: A Preliminary Review, Publication (Box 5, Folder 13)
    By Robert D. Bhaerman. Quest Paper No. 10. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Collective Bargaining and the Teaching Learning Process, Publication (Box 5, Folder 13)
    By John G. Sperling. Quest Paper No. 11. Item is in English.
- Box 5, Folder (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Public Benefits Associated with Public Expenditures in Education, Publication (Box 5, Folder 14)
    By Raymond Floren, Jr.; J. William Leasure; Marjorie S. Turner. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Summary Findings on the North East Regional Conference on Quality Educational Standards in Teaching, Publication (Box 5, Folder 14)
    By American Federation of Teachers. Quest Report No. 1. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Education's New Dualisms, Publication (Box 5, Folder 14)
    By Robert D. Rhaerman. Quest Paper No. 8. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Instructional Technology and the Teaching Profession, Publication (Box 5, Folder 14)
    By David Selden. Quest Paper No. 6. Item is in English.
- Box 5, Folder (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: The National Economy 1973, Publication (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Item 2: The National Economy 1979, Publication (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Box 5, Folder (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Labor Looks at the National Economy, Publication (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Box 5, Folder (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Meany on Controls, Publication (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Item 2: The New Nixon Game Plan, Publication (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Item 3: The Nixon Economic Program, Publication (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Item 4: Price Controls and You, Publication (Box 5, Folder 17)
    By Executive Office of the President. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: The Problems Facing the Economy, Publication (Box 5, Folder 17)
    By Leonard Woodcock. January 26, 1971; Statement made before the Joint Economic Committee. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Statement on the Economic Report of the President, Publication (Box 5, Folder 17)
    By Leonard Woodcock. March 11, 1971; Statement made before the Joint Economic Committee. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Statement on the President's State of the Union Message, Publication (Box 5, Folder 17)
    By Leaonard Woodcock. January 26, 1971; Statement made before the Joint Economic Committee. Item is in English.
- Box 5, Folder (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: Assessing the Economic Scene, Publication (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Item 2: The Economy: Private Initiative and Public Responsibility, Publication (Box 5, Folder 18)
    By Gabriel Hauge. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Looking Forward: The Abundant Society, Publication (Box 5, Folder 18)
    By Center for the Study of Democractic Institutions. Collection of papers by various authors. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Statement before the Subcommittee on Economy in Government of the Joint Economic Committee, Publication (Box 5, Folder 18)
    By Walter P. Reuther. June 9, 1969. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Statement before the Subcommittee on Economy in the Government of the Joint Economic Committee, Publication (Box 5, Folder 18)
    By Leonard Woodcock. June 16, 1970. Item is in English.
- Box 5, Folder (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: Maintaining Prosperity, Publication (Box 5, Folder 19)
    By Congress of Industrial Organizations. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Cut the Budget - How and Where, Publication (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Item 3: The Public Debt and What To Do About It, Publication (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Item 4: Bring Government Back Home, Publication (Box 5, Folder 19)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. Revised Summary Edition. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: The Conflict Between Stable Prices and Maximum Employment, Publication (Box 5, Folder 19)
    By Sumnher H. Slichter. Multiple editorials stapled together. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: The Fallacy of Controlled Prices, Publication (Box 5, Folder 19)
    By Herrell De Graff. Taken from a broadcast by De Graff over Liberty Radio Network. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Economic Progress in a Rearmed World, Publication (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Item 8: Business Cycle Research and the Needs of Our Times, Publication (Box 5, Folder 19)
    By Arthur F. Burns. Item is in English.
- Box 5, Folder (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: Wages and Profits in Wartime, Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
    By Labor Research Association. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Testimony on the President's Economic Report, Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
    By Emerson P. Schmidt. February 7, 1962. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Do You Know Your Economic ABC's?, Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Item 4: The Federal Budget and "The General Welfare", Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Item 5: Labor, Management and Government View the Economy, Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
    By Jack Chernick. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Jobs and Growth, Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Item 7: The People and 1960, Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
    By Dewey Anderson and Associates; Alexander Uhl; Harry Conn. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: The Workingman Views the Economic Scene Today; Wives Speak Out on School Prayer, Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
    By Macfadden-Bartell Corporation. A report from The Forum, Vol 64. No. 14. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: The Creative Power of Profits, Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
    By John D. Lockton. Talk given at Macalester College on April 22, 1964. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Our Common Cause in World Competition, Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
    By Fred J. Borch. Address before The Economic Club of New York on November 9, 1964. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: The Nation's Workers, Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
    By Macfadden-Bartell Corporation. Report to management from The Forum vol 63, No. 1. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: The Private Impact of Public Spending, Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
    By Robert C. Tyson. Address before the Public Expenditure Survey of Wisconsin on September 29, 1964. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: Long-Range Projection for Economic Growth: the American Economy in 1970, Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
    By National Planning Association. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: Unionism and Income Distribution, Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
    By Arthur M. Ross. Lecture at Wayne University on February 21, 1950. Item is in English.
  - Item 15: Happy Ending, Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
    By Frank Rising. Economic analysis reprinted from the Detroit Free Press of July 28, 1949. Item is in English.
- Box 5, Folder (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: Defense Against Recession: Policy for Greater Economic Stability, Publication (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Item 2: The Economic Outlook for 1956, Publication (Box 5, Folder 21)
    By George P. Hitchings; Edwin B. George; Edwin G. Nourse; Stanley H. Ruttenberg. Proceedings for the Conference on The Economic Outlook for 1956. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Current Economic Trends (Where Are We Going?), Publication (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Item 4: Basic Economics, March 1954, Publication (Box 5, Folder 21)
    By University of Chicago, Industrial Relations Center. Bibliography; from Industrial Relations Libraries Exchange Bibliographies No. 872. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Why the American Economy is Depression-Proof, Publication (Box 5, Folder 21)
    By Milton Friedman. From the Occasional Papers in Management - Organization - Industrial Relations, No. 18. Item is in English; German.
  - Item 6: A New Force for Inflation, Publication (Box 5, Folder 21)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. Not in German. Item is in English; German.
  - Item 7: Facing the Issue of Income Tax Discrimination, Publication (Box 5, Folder 21)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. A statement on the Five-Year Income Tax Reduction Plan; Not in German. Item is in English; German.
  - Item 8: Can We Depression-Proof Our Economy?, Publication (Box 5, Folder 21)
    By U.S Chamber of Commerce. Item is in English.
- Box 6, Folder (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: National Apprenticeship and Training Standards for the Electrical Industry, Publication (Box 6, Folder 1)
    By U.S Department of Labor. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: A Strikeless Industry: A Co-operative Plan for Adjusting Industrial Relations, Publication (Box 6, Folder 1)
    By M. H. Hedges. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Analysis of Electrical Union Contracts in Manufacturing - 1956, Publication (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Analysis of Electrical Union Contracts in Manufacturing, Publication (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: Analysis of Electrical Union Contracts in Manufacturing, Publication (Box 6, Folder 1)
    By National Industrial Conference Board, Inc. Copy 2. Item is in English.
- Box 6, Folder (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Computers: A General Management Viewpoint, Publication (Box 6, Folder 2)
    By Hershner Cross. Address in the Leatherbee Lecture Series; February 28, 1967. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The Growing Maturity of the Computer Age, Publication (Box 6, Folder 2)
    By J. Stanford Smith. Address to Data Processing Management Association on June 26, 1968. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Electronic Data Processing and Personnel Management, Publication (Box 6, Folder 2)
    By University of California Los Angeles, Institute of Industrial Relations. Proceedings of a conference held on July 29, 1965; various authors/speakers. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Information Processing Industry Personnel, Publication (Box 6, Folder 2)
    By Merrill M. Flood. Item is in English.
- Box 6, Folder (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Electrical Machinery, Equipment, and Supplies Industry, 1950-1971, Publication (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: Collective Bargaining in the Electrical Manufacturing Industry, Publication (Box 6, Folder 3)
    By Illinois University, Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations. Bibliography. Item is in English.
- Box 6, Folder (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Making It Go, Publication (Box 6, Folder 4)
    By Stephen L. Cook; Miles C. Stanley. Item is in English.
- Box 6, Folder (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Collective Bargaining in Higher Education; The Coming Slums of Higher Education?; Academic Freedom Countervailing Forces New Governance, Old Problems, Publication (Box 6, Folder 5)
    By Donald E. Walters; Thomas B. Corcoran; Bardwell L. Smith. AGB Reports Vol 15, No 6; Collection of reports from the National Conference on Trusteeship. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Administrators in the Process of Unionization Avoiding Unfair Labor Practices, Publication (Box 6, Folder 5)
    By Tracy H. Ferguson; William L. Bergan. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Collective Bargaining in Education: An Annotated Bibliography, Publication (Box 6, Folder 5)
    By Catherine R. Dobson. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Administrators and University Employees, Publication (Box 6, Folder 5)
    By Al Bilik. Speech given at the Conference of the College and University Personnel Association on October 15, 1973. Item is in English.
- Box 6, Folder (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Collective Bargaining: Implications for Governance, Publication (Box 6, Folder 6)
    By Kenneth P. Mortimer; G. Gregory Lozier. Report No 17 for Center for the Study of Higher Education. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Unionism at the University of Michigan, Publication (Box 6, Folder 6)
    By Donald A. Morris. December 1, 1965. Item is in English.
- Box 6, Folder (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Foremanship: Fundamentals in the Development of Industrial Foremen, Publication (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Item 2: For Better Understanding: The Purpose and Organization of Foremen's Clubs, Publication (Box 6, Folder 7)
    By National Association of Foremen. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Improving Foremanship, Publication (Box 6, Folder 7)
    By U.S. Federal Board for Vocational Education. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Instructor Training, Publication (Box 6, Folder 7)
    By U.S. Federal Board for Vocational Education. Instructor-training courses for trade teachers. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: The Training of Foreman Conference Leaders, Publication (Box 6, Folder 7)
    By U.S.Department of the Interior. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: How to Instruct, Publication (Box 6, Folder 7)
    By Glenn Gardiner and Associates. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Typical Foremanship Programs and topics, Winter 1926-1927, Publication (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Item 8: Manual for Leaders of Foremanship Conferences together with Discussion Outlines, Publication (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Item 9: Foremanship Courses vs Instructor-Training Courses, Publication (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Item 10: Report of a Training Course for Foreman Conference Leaders, Publication (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Item 11: Bibliography on Foreman Improvement, Publication (Box 6, Folder 7)
    By U.S. Department of the Interior. Item is in English.
- Box 6, Folder (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Management Personnel Planning, Publication (Box 6, Folder 8)
    By McKinsey & Company. Two reports in one booklet: "Executive Development Today for Increased Profits Tomorrow" and "Developing Executives for Business Leadership". Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The Selection and Development of Executives, Publication (Box 6, Folder 8)
    By Princeton University, Industrial Relations Section. Bibliography; from Selected References No. 28. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Organizing and Developing the Management Team, Publication (Box 6, Folder 8)
    By Ewing W. Reilley. Address at Conferences. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Education for Management, Publication (Box 6, Folder 8)
    By L. A. Appley. Paper presented at the Ixth International Management Congress. Item is in English.
- Box 6, Folder (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Information for Employer Members of Local Panels Regional War Labor Boards, Publication (Box 6, Folder 9)
    By U.S. National War Labor Board. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The National Association of Foreman: What It Means to You, Publication (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Item 3: Management Training Programs in Industry, Publication (Box 6, Folder 9)
    By Harvard University. Final report of a questionnaire study. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Proceedings C.C.C. Foreman Training Conference, Publication (Box 6, Folder 9)
    By U.S. Civilian Conservation Corps. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Series of Talks to New York City WPA Executives as Part of the Executive Training Program, Publication (Box 6, Folder 9)
    By WPA. Five reports bound together. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Report on Work of a Conference Leader Training Course, Publication (Box 6, Folder 9)
    By U.S. Office of Education. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: The Selection and Development of Prospective Foremen, Publication (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Item 8: The Selection and Development of Executives, Publication (Box 6, Folder 9)
    By Princeton University, Industrial Relations Section. Bibliography; Selected References No. 11. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Organizing for Management Education, Publication (Box 6, Folder 9)
    By R. C. Muir; Forest D. Siefkin. Two papers presented at the General Management Conference: "An Experiment in Mangement Education" and "Training Management to Meet Labor". Item is in English.
  - Item 10: CCC Foremanship, Publication (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Box 6, Folder (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Rate Your Supervisor, Publication (Box 6, Folder 10)
    By Esso Research and Engineering Co. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: An Action Research Program for Organization Improvement (in Esso Standard Oil Company), Publication (Box 6, Folder 10)
    By Barbara Peek. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Development - As a Function of Personnel Management, Publication (Box 6, Folder 10)
    By Alina L. Hopkins. Collection of papers given at the 1961 Personnel Management Conference on March 12-14, 1961. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Legal Education for the Businessman, Publication (Box 6, Folder 10)
    By L. I. Wood. Conference on Education for Business on July 28, 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Implications for Future Managerial Education, Publication (Box 6, Folder 10)
    By Harold F. Smiddy. Conference on Education for Business on July 24, 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Supervisors Manual for Business Internship Program, Publication (Box 6, Folder 10)
    By Mead Johnson Institute. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Organization Planning's Recommended Management Reading List, Publication (Box 6, Folder 10)
    By International Milling Co. Correspondence from University of Michigan attached. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Supervisor Training, Publication (Box 6, Folder 10)
    By James L. Davenport. From Address on Industrial Relations. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Evalution of Management Development: A Bibliography, Publication (Box 6, Folder 10)
    By Robert J. House; J. Michael Keenan. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Theory of Management Development, Publication (Box 6, Folder 10)
    By Robert J. House. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Training in Industry: A Survey of Training Investments by California Business Firms, Publication (Box 6, Folder 10)
    By David S. Bushnell. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: The Hard Road to Management Development, Publication (Box 6, Folder 10)
    By Robert J. House. From Management of Personnel Quarterly Vol. 1, No. 4. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: Executive Development Programme, Publication (Box 6, Folder 10)
    By British Institute of Management. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: How Do People Grow In a Business Organization?, Publication (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Item 15: The Education of Businessmen, Publication (Box 6, Folder 10)
    By Leonard S. Silk. Item is in English.
  - Item 16: Management Development: A Norwegian Experiment, Publication (Box 6, Folder 10)
    By Rolf Waaler. Three Leatherbee lectures. Item is in English.
- Box 6, Folder (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Management Development: The Hope and the Reality, Publication (Box 6, Folder 11)
    By Douglas McGregor. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Executive Development in the Small Company, Publication (Box 6, Folder 11)
    By Louis A. Allen. From Address on Industrial Relations. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: A Critical Appraisal of Executive Development Programs, Publication (Box 6, Folder 11)
    By R. Carter Wellford. From Address on Industrial Relations. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: How Do Pepole Grow in a Business organization?, Publication (Box 6, Folder 11)
    By Moorhead Wright. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Work Plan for Training Programs, Publication (Box 6, Folder 11)